VIGNESH MARIAPPAN

FRONT END JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

GET TO KNOW ME

Accomplished Software
Engineer with **5 years** of
experience in developing web
applications using various
front end technologies.
Involved in few back end
activities

PERSONAL SKILLS

Creative spirit
Time management
Team player
Quick learner & motivated

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

worked as an Engineer in
Renault Nissan Technology
and Business Centre India
Private Limited from July
2017 to Jan 2020

working as a **Research & Development Engineer** in **Dassault Systemes** from Jan

2020 till present.

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

To work in a spirited environment which provides opportunities to learn new things, while I can share knowledge and utilize my experience in best possible ways for achieving company goals in a challenging work environment.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Provided technical leadership on the architecture, design and successful implementation of applications using **HTML 5**, **CSS 3**, **SCSS**, **JavaScript (ES 5 & ES 6)**, **Bootstrap 4**, **React JS**.

Used **responsive web design** templates to meet cutting-edge technology requirements.

Strong knowledge in JavaScript framework **React JS**

Participated in ongoing initiatives to improve processes and establish best practices.

Good knowledge in consuming **REST APIs** using **AJAX** calls in PLM domain.

Experienced in Agile methodology.

Able to communicate effectively, with both technical and non-technical stakeholders

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Bachelor of Engineering

BE in Electronics &
Communication Engineering
from **SSN College of Engineering** under Anna
University, Chennai, Tamil
Nadu in the year 2013 - 2017
with **CGPA 7.5**

12th [2012 - 2013]

12th in Green Park Matric. Hr. Sec. School, Namakkal, Tamil Nadu with the **percentage of 96.4.**

10th [2010 - 2011]

10th in CKT Matric. Hr. Sec. School, Kovilpatti, Tamil Nadu with the **percentage of 93.8.**

PERSONAL DETAILS

Nationality

Indian

Date of birth

23 - DEC - 1995

Permanent address

1 / 191, Sarathy street, Amaravathy Nagar, Jalladianpet, Chennai.

Languages known

English, Tamil

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web technologies

HTML 5, CSS 3, SCSS, JavaScript (ES 5 & ES6), Bootstrap 4, ReactJS, Require JS

Programming languages

Java, JDBC

IDE tools

MS VS code, Brackets, Eclipse, IBM RAD

Application servers

Apache Tomcat, Websphere server

Databases

Oracle SQL 11g

Unit testing frameworks

Jasmine, Karma, Leadfoot

PROJECT UNDERTAKEN - RENAULT

DEALER MASTER DATA

Description

The **DMD** application is used to provide Dealers data information's with their contract level 1 & level 2 throughout the world. Mainly this application is used to send data to all other applications (like commercial, warranty, sales, distribution & logistics).

Responsibilites

- Designed & developed user interfaces using HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript.
- Writing business logic using core Java.
- Fix issues and providing enhancements to customers on time. It involved in getting an overall picture of the module and knowledge of how it integrates with the other module.
- Requirement analysis & discussion with business people regarding current and upcoming changes.
- Involved in full SDLC like designing, coding, testing & maintenance.

WORK WITH ME!

Mobile: **+91 9884802312** Alternate: **+91 8778221313**

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vignesh-m-432606139/

Mail:

vigneshmv2312@gmail.comGitHub:

https://github.com/Vignesh-Mariappan

Portfolio url: https://vignesh-mariappan.github.io/vignesh-portfolio/

OTHER PROJECTS

Website url: https://vigneshmariappan.github.io/vignesh--projects/

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above mentioned practices

PROJECT UNDERTAKEN - DASSAULT

ENOVIA CONFIGURATION Description

ENOVIA Configuration is used in many Automobiles, Aviation and other industries for the better life cycle management of the products and their configuration, Users can define configurations for evaluation purposes in order and prevent invalid feature combinations that are not technically supported. It helps companies to reduce unnecessary product diversity and increase product reuse by allowing product engineers to search for existing configurations that satisfy market needs.

Responsibilites

- Responsible for new enhancements / features development in the application.
- Implemented best practices to JavaScript codebase, develop new functionality and create new layouts.
- Consuming REST APIs
- Find and fix bugs in the application
- Sharing new proposals for enhancements / use-cases(wireframing) using Whimsical tool and Figma
- Write and test ODT(Object Driven Test Cases) using Jasmine, Karma & Leadfoot
- Work with NLS team to make application
 Internationalization
- Mentoring new members in the team
- Responsible for sharing knowledge of new features of scripting in the team
- Strong oral and written communication skills with the ability to communicate technical and non-technical concepts to peers
- Using ESLINT to avoid problematic patterns found in the JavaScript code and to follow the best coding practices